Finding Aid for Clarence Cook Little Papers 1924-1929
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Clarence Cook Little papers 1924-1929
Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), b. 1888.
President of the University of Michigan, 1924-1929, educational reformer, geneticist and cancer researcher, also interested in a range of reform movement including birth control, eugenics, international peace, and immigration. Papers include correspondence, speeches and reports concerning all phases of his career as president of the University of Michigan and his civic and reform activities.
851744 Aa 2 UAm
14 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection is open for research.
Clarence C. Little, biologist, genetics and cancer researcher, was President of the University of Michigan, 1925-1929. Born Oct. 6, 1888 in Brookline, Massachusetts, Little was a graduate of Harvard (A.B. 1910; S.M. Graduate School of Applied Science 1912; Sc.D. 1914) where he served as secretary of the Harvard Corporation while completing graduate work in biology and genetics. He held several research positions at Harvard 1911-1918. He continued his research work at Cold Spring Harbor, Long Island, and in 1921 became Assistant Director of the Station for Experimental Evaluation, Carnegie Institute. A year later he was appointed president of the University of Maine. Following is tenure at Michigan, Little served as director of the Jackson Memorial Laboratory, 1929-1956 (emeritus director 1956-1971). Little died December 22, 1971.
Following President Burton's death in February 1925, Dean Alfred Lloyd was appointed Acting President, while a committee consisting of three Regents -- William Clements, Junius Beal, and Walter Sawyer -- and three faculty members -- G. C. Huber, Jesse Reeves, and Herbert Sadler -- undertook the selection of a president. After a thorough search, the Board of Regents chose Clarence Cook Little, then the President of the University of Maine. He accepted the appointment and took office in September 1925. When Little came to the University of Michigan, the regents agreed to let him bring two assistants and continue his laboratory research on the inheritance of cancer here. He was a excellent scholar and outspoken regarding his progressive educational views.
In his inaugural address, President Little made a number of specific proposals and set forth his innovative ideas on which they were based. These included the belief that only those students deemed able to make the best use of education should be admitted to universities, that students should be taught to think for themselves, and that more attention should be paid to the individual student and his needs. He also believed that the resources, equipment and staff of the university should be available to the whole state.
The major project undertaken during his administration was the University College, based on his belief that the first two years of basic general studies should be separated from the last two years of specialization. At the request of the regents, the University Senate created the Committee on Undergraduate Studies in January 1927. (Records of this committee can be found in record group: University of Michigan. University College.) Although their plan, when it was completed, met with general approval, the faculties of Literature, Science, and the Arts and the Engineering College both raised objections. Nevertheless, the regents authorized the appointment of an executive committee to prepare for the establishment of the new college to be opened in September 1929. Planning was suspended after President Little submitted his resignation in January 1929, and the program was never implemented.
In spite of the controversial nature of many of his proposals, President Little's administration was marked by several major accomplishments. These included Freshman Week, a period just before the fall term when incoming students were introduced to university life, and the Alumni University, designed to make the university an ongoing part of alumni life. Although it did not survive in its original form, it led to the establishment of the Bureau of Alumni Relations and the strengthening of ties between the university and its graduates. He also initiated the plan to house all students in university dormitories.
Although President Little's ideas had initially met with a favorable response, his forthright approach and a lack of skill in personal relations resulted in increased friction within the university. In addition, his outspoken views on birth control and eugenics alienated sectors of the public. Thus, when his letter of resignation was presented to the regents, it did not come as a complete surprise, and it was accepted to become effective September l, 1929.
The collection is arranged chronologically with individual folders in alphabetical order within each year. The basic arrangement within each folder is from later to earlier date, although usage over the years has led to disarrangement in some folders. The numbers in square brackets refer to box and folder numbers.
The C.C. Little papers document a wide range to topics, events, administrative actions, policy developments during Little's tenure as president of the University of Michigan. The collection contains mainly reports and replies to letters but very little incoming correspondence. However, the researcher may use these replies as clues to other collections in the library which contain the individual correspondent's papers.
The chronological ordering of the papers makes subject access somewhat difficult. To selective indexes of correspondents and subjects found in the papers provide some assistance in using the Little papers. The following discussion of the papers follows the structure of the subject index.
The growth of the university which had begun at the close of World War I continued to be felt during President Little's tenure. New buildings completed earlier were handling classroom and laboratory needs, so attention now turned to living accommodations and the athletic department's needs (Sec. II). The period of the 1920s was one of increased interest in theories of progressive education. President's Little's primary interest was in educational policy arising from such theories. Thus, academic and departmental proposals and reorganizations (Sec. III of the subject index) form a major part of his papers. He made fewer administrative changes (Sec. I of the subject index). The twenties are also remembered as a time of social ferment in the country and this was reflected in campus life, with more attention being paid to regulating student social mores and the use of alcohol and cars (see Secs. I and IV of the subject index).
Although President Little oversaw the reorganization of some administrative offices, his attention was mainly focused on educational policy, his primary interest. This is reflected in materials on admissions policy, freshman orientation, continuing education of alumni, and the re-organization of the university into two separate units.
A few months after President Little took office, the "Day Report", so named because Edmund Day, Dean of the School of Business Administration chaired the committee which drew it up, was completed. It was the result of an exhaustive study of athletics, physical education and recreation in the university and led to changes in the Board in Control of Athletics, development of women's and intramural athletics, and gave impetus to the financing and building of the stadium (opened in 1927).
President Little's concern with developing students of good moral character resulted in regulation of the use of cars and alcohol, thought to be related twin evils, and the initiation of planning for dormitories, where all students would live under university supervision.
The major building projects that came to fruition during the Little Administration were the Stadium and the Women's League Building. Construction work at the Law School and the School of Education represented on-going projects begun in earlier administrations, while plans for a natural science museum were just beginning to take shape.
During President Little's tenure, schools and departments established earlier continued to grow, while some projects, such as the Creative Arts Fellowship, were brought to a close. The financing and governance of the Lawyers' Club presented on-going difficulties. Compensation for and the role of "outside work" in Medicine, Engineering, and Education required continued attention. The university contributed to scientific research through the Hobbs Expedition to Greenland which also showed the value of the university's fledgling radio program in maintaining communication with such distant projects.
With the appointment of Samuel Trask Dana as Dean, the School of Forestry was established in the spring of 1927. At that time the state was faced with the problems of cutover lands and the collapse of the lumbering industry. In 1927 the School of Forestry provided leadership in dealing with these problems by sponsoring two conferences which brought together owners and operators in the lumbering industry, state officials, and forestry experts to consider solutions.
The School of Education continued its growth with the addition of an elementary school building. The completion of that building in 1929 enabled the School to provide K-12 education under the supervision of its faculty. Some attention was given also to providing pre-primary education, but nothing came of this during Little's tenure.
The university and its academic life did not escape the impact of the societal upheavals of the "roaring twenties". Perhaps more so at the University of Michigan because of President Little's active role in several of those issues, as is reflected in his correspondence. He was an officer in the American Eugenics Society, a vocal proponent of both population control and the "betterment of the human race", and also served as chairman of the Michigan chapter of the League of Nations Non-partisan Association.
Subjects:
Adult education.; Aeronautics.; African Americans.; Authors, American--Michigan.; Birth control.; Drug abuse.; Education--United States.; United States--Emigration and immigration.; Eugenics.; Jews.; Jews--United States.; Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), b. 1888.; Narcotics.; Peace--Societies, etc.; Prohibition--United States.; Public health--United States.; Temperance--United States.; University of Michigan--Administration.; University of Michigan. President.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; Immigrants--United States.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), b. 1888.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
University of Michigan--History.
Contributors:
America Asia Association.; American Association Favoring Reconsideration of the War Debts.; American Association for Adult Education.; American Birth Control League.; American Christian Fund for Jewish Relief.; American Council on Education.; American Eugenics Society.; American Peace Society.; American Social Hygiene Association.; Anti-Saloon League of America.; Bates, Henry Moore, 1869-1949.; Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.; Bishop, William Warner, 1871-1955.; Bureau of Social Hygiene (New York, N.Y.); Butterfield, Kenyon L. (Kenyon Leech), 1868-1935.; Chapin, Roy D. (Roy Dikeman), 1880-1936.; Clancy, Robert Henry, 1882-1962.; Clements, William L. (William Lawrence), 1861-1934.; Committee on Social Analysis of College Communities.; Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.; Copeland, Royal S. (Royal Samuel), 1868-1938.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Dana, Samuel Trask, 1883-1978; Davis, Dwight Filley, 1879-1945.; Day, Edmund Ezra, 1883-1951.; Effinger, John Robert, 1869-1933.; English Speaking Union.; Ferris, Woodbridge N., 1853-1928.; Ford, Edsel, 1893-1943.; Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963.; Green, Fred W. (Fred Warren), 1872-1936.; Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Alexander Joseph), 1873-1953.; Daniel Guggenheim Fund for the Promotion of Aeronautics.; Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1887-1945.; Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Illinois Birth Control League.; Immigration Restriction League.; Institute of International Education (New York, N.Y.); Kellogg, Frank B. (Frank Billings), 1856-1937.; Life Conservation League. Dept. of Loyalty to Law.; Lloyd, Alfred H. (Alfred Henry), 1864-1927.; Lorch, Emil, 1870-1963.; Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967.; Malthusian League for Human Welfare through Birth Control.; Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.; Michigan Authors' Association.; Mott, Charles Stewart, 1875-1973.; Murfin, James Orin, 1875-1940.; Negro-Caucasian Club.; Negro National Educational Congress.; Non-Partisan Association for the League of Nations.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Rackham, Horace H., 1858-1933.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Sink, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1879-1972.; Smith, Shirley Wheeler, 1875-1959.; Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis), 1867-1950.; Sundwall, John, 1880-1950.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Van Tyne, Claude Halstead, 1869-1930.; Ward, Marcus Llewellyn, 1875-1963.; Whitney, Allen Sisson, 1857-1944.; World Alliance for International Friendship through the Churches.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Papers (Chronological)
  - 1924-1925
    - A (Box 1)
      [1-1]
    - American Council on Education (Box 1)
      [1-2]
    - Ba-Bh (Box 1)
      [1-3]
    - Bi-Bz (Box 1)
      [1-4]
    - Ca-Ch (Box 1)
      [1-5]
    - Ci-Cz (Box 1)
      [1-6]
    - D (Box 1)
      [1-7]
    - E (Box 1)
      [1-8]
    - F-G (Box 1)
      [1-9]
    - H-J (Box 1)
      [1-10]
    - K-L (Box 1)
      [1-11]
    - M-O (Box 1)
      [1-12]
    - P-Q (Box 1)
      [1-13]
    - R (Box 1)
      [1-14]
    - S (Box 1)
      [1-15]
    - T-V (Box 1)
      [1-16]
    - W-Z (Box 1)
      [1-17]
  - 1925-1926
    - Aa-Ai (Box 1)
      [1-18]
    - Aj-Az (Box 1)
      [1-19]
    - American Association for Medical Progress (Box 1)
      [1-20]
    - American Council on Education (Box 1)
      [1-21]
    - Baa-Baz (Box 1)
      [1-22]
    - Bates, Henry (Box 1)
      [1-23]
    - Bea-Bez (Box 1)
      [1-24]
    - Beal, Junius (Box 1)
      [1-25]
    - Bi-Bl (Box 1)
      [1-26]
    - Bishop, William Warner (Box 1)
      [1-27]
    - Bm-Br (Box 1)
      [1-28]
    - Bua-Buz (Box 1)
      [1-29]
    - Bursley, J.A. (Box 1)
      [1-30]
    - Caa-Caz (Box 1)
      [1-31]
    - Cabot, Hugh (Box 1)
      [1-32]
    - Ce-Ch (Box 2)
      [2-1]
    - Ci-Cl (Box 2)
      [2-2]
    - Clements, William (Box 2)
      [2-3]
    - Clements Library (Box 2)
      [2-4]
    - Coa-Con (Box 2)
      [2-5]
    - Coo-Coz (Box 2)
      [2-6]
    - Cooley, Mortimer Elwyn (Box 2)
      [2-7]
    - Cp-Cz (Box 2)
      [2-8]
    - Da-De (Box 2)
      [2-9]
    - Di-Dz (Box 2)
      [2-10]
    - Ea-Ez (Box 2)
      [2-11]
    - Effinger, John (Box 2)
      [2-12]
    - Fa-Fh (Box 2)
      [2-13]
    - Fi-Fl (Box 2)
      [2-14]
    - Fm-Fz (Box 2)
      [2-15]
    - Ga-Gl (Box 2)
      [2-16]
    - Goa-Gz (Box 2)
      [2-17]
    - Gore, Victor (Box 2)
      [2-18]
    - Haa-Haz (Box 2)
      [2-19]
    - Hamilton, Jean (Box 2)
      [2-20]
    - Hanchett, Benjamin (Box 2)
      [2-21]
    - Haynes, Harley (Box 2)
      [2-22]
    - Hea-Hi (Box 2)
      [2-23]
    - Hoa-Hoz (Box 2)
      [2-24]
    - Hobbs Expedition-Greenland (Box 2)
      [2-25]
    - Hua-Hz (Box 2)
      [2-26]
    - Hubbard, Lucius Lee (Box 2)
      [2-27]
    - I (Box 2)
      [2-28]
    - Institute of International Education (Box 2)
      [2-29]
    - J (Box 2)
      [2-30]
    - Johnson, Thomas E. (Box 2)
      [2-31]
    - Ka-Kz (Box 2)
      [2-32]
    - Kelsey, Francis (Box 2)
      [2-33]
    - Laa-Lz (Box 2)
      [2-34]
    - Lawyers' Club Minutes (Box 2)
      [2-35]
    - Lloyd, Alfred Henry (Box 2)
      [2-36]
    - Maa-Maz (Box 2)
      [2-37]
    - McA-McZ (Box 2)
      [2-38]
    - Me-Mi (Box 2)
      [2-39]
    - Moa-Mz (Box 3)
      [3-1]
    - Murfin, James (Box 3)
      [3-2]
    - Na-Nh (Box 3)
      [3-3]
    - Ni-Nz (Box 3)
      [3-4]
    - O (Box 3)
      [3-5]
    - P-Q (Box 3)
      [3-6]
    - Pardon, E.C. (Box 3)
      [3-7]
    - Ra-Rn (Box 3)
      [3-8]
    - ROTC (Box 3)
      [3-9]
    - Ro-Rz (Box 3)
      [3-10]
    - Ruthven, Alexander Grant (Box 3)
      [3-11]
    - Sa-Sh (Box 3)
      [3-12]
    - Sawyer, Walter (Box 3)
      [3-13]
    - Si-Sq (Box 3)
      [3-14]
    - Smith, Shirley Wheeler (Box 3)
      [3-15]
    - Smith, Shirley Wheeler (Box 3)
      [3-16]
    - St-Sz (Box 3)
      [3-17]
    - Stone, Ralph (Box 3)
      [3-18]
    - Sundwall, John (Box 3)
      [3-19]
    - Ta-Tz (Box 3)
      [3-20]
    - Treasurer's Reports (Box 3)
      [3-21]
    - U (Box 3)
      [3-22]
    - V (Box 3)
      [3-23]
    - Waa-Waz (Box 3)
      [3-24]
    - Wb-Wh (Box 3)
      [3-25]
    - Whitney, Allen Sisson (Box 3)
      [3-26]
    - Wia-Wz (Box 3)
      [3-27]
    - Women's League Minutes (Box 3)
      [3-28]
    - X-Z (Box 3)
      [3-29]
    - Yost, Fielding (Box 3)
      [3-30]
  - 1926-1927
    - Aa-An (Box 4)
      [4-1]
    - American Birth Control League (Box 4)
      [4-2]
    - American Council on Education (Box 4)
      [4-3]
    - Ao-Az (Box 4)
      [4-4]
    - Ba-Be (Box 4)
      [4-5]
    - Bates, Henry (Box 4)
      [4-6]
    - Beal, Junius (Box 4)
      [4-7]
    - Bi-Bo (Box 4)
      [4-8]
    - Bishop, William Warner (Box 4)
      [4-9]
    - Br-Bz (Box 4)
      [4-10]
    - Bursley, J.A. (Box 4)
      [4-11]
    - Caa-Caz (Box 4)
      [4-12]
    - Cabot, Hugh (Box 4)
      [4-13]
    - Ce-Cok (Box 4)
      [4-14]
    - Clements, William (Box 4)
      [4-15]
    - Clements Library (Box 4)
      [4-16]
    - Col-Coz (Box 4)
      [4-17]
    - Cook, W.W. (Box 4)
      [4-18]
    - Cooley, Mortimer Elwyn (Box 4)
      [4-19]
    - Cp-Cz (Box 4)
      [4-20]
    - Da-Di (Box 4)
      [4-21]
    - Doa-Dz (Box 4)
      [4-22]
    - Ea-Eh (Box 4)
      [4-23]
    - Effinger, John Robert (Box 4)
      [4-24]
    - Ei-Ez (Box 4)
      [4-25]
    - Executive Committee (Box 4)
      [4-26]
    - Fa-Fl (Box 4)
      [4-27]
    - Fo-Fz (Box 4)
      [4-28]
    - Ga-Goz (Box 4)
      [4-29]
    - Gore, Victor (Box 4)
      [4-30]
    - Governor's Committee (Box 4)
      [4-31]
    - Gr-Gz (Box 4)
      [4-32]
    - Haa-Haz (Box 5)
      [5-1]
    - Haynes, Harley (Box 5)
      [5-2]
    - Hea-Hi (Box 5)
      [5-3]
    - High School Inspection (Box 5)
      [5-4]
    - Hoa-Hz (Box 5)
      [5-5]
    - I (Box 5)
      [5-6]
    - J (Box 5)
      [5-7]
    - K (Box 5)
      [5-8]
    - La-Li (Box 5)
      [5-9]
    - Ll-Lz (Box 5)
      [5-10]
    - Maa-Maz (Box 5)
      [5-11]
    - McA-McZ (Box 5)
      [5-12]
    - Mea-Mi (Box 5)
      [5-13]
    - Michigan League (Box 5)
      [5-14]
    - Michigan League (Box 5)
      [5-15]
    - Moa-Mz (Box 5)
      [5-16]
    - Murfin, James (Box 5)
      [5-17]
    - N (Box 5)
      [5-18]
    - O (Box 5)
      [5-19]
    - Pa-Pe (Box 5)
      [5-20]
    - Pf-Po (Box 5)
      [5-21]
    - Pr-Pz (Box 5)
      [5-22]
    - Q (Box 5)
      [5-23]
    - Ra-Re (Box 5)
      [5-24]
    - Rh-Ri (Box 5)
      [5-25]
    - Riggs, Francis E. (Box 5)
      [5-26]
    - Ro (Box 6)
      [6-1]
    - Rotary Club (Box 6)
      [6-2]
    - ROTC (Box 6)
      [6-3]
    - Ru-Rz (Box 6)
      [6-4]
    - Sa-Sh (Box 6)
      [6-5]
    - Sawyer, Walter (Box 6)
      [6-6]
    - Si-Sl (Box 6)
      [6-7]
    - Simpson Memorial-Dedication (Box 6)
      [6-8]
    - Smith, Shirley Wheeler (Box 6)
      [6-9]
    - Smith (various) (Box 6)
      [6-10]
    - Sn-So (Box 6)
      [6-11]
    - Stone, Ralph (Box 6)
      [6-12]
    - St (Box 6)
      [6-13]
    - Student Christian Association (Box 6)
      [6-14]
    - Su-Sz (Box 6)
      [6-15]
    - Ta-Tz (Box 6)
      [6-16]
    - Treasurer's Report (Box 6)
      [6-17]
    - U (Box 6)
      [6-18]
    - V (Box 6)
      [6-19]
    - Waa-Wez (Box 6)
      [6-20]
    - Ward, Marcus Llewelyn (Box 6)
      [6-21]
    - Wh (Box 6)
      [6-22]
    - Whitney, Allen Sisson (Box 6)
      [6-23]
    - Wia-Wil (Box 6)
      [6-24]
    - Wim-Wz (Box 6)
      [6-25]
    - World Population Conference (Box 6)
      [6-26]
    - X-Z (Box 6)
      [6-27]
    - Yost, Fielding Harris (Box 6)
      [6-28]
  - 1927-1928
    - Aa-Ai (Box 7)
      [7-1]
    - Alumni Association (Box 7)
      [7-2]
    - Alumni Association (Box 7)
      [7-3]
    - Alumni Club (Box 7)
      [7-4]
    - Aj-An (Box 7)
      [7-5]
    - American Birth Control League (Box 7)
      [7-6]
    - American Council on Education (Box 7)
      [7-7]
    - American Eugenics Society (Box 7)
      [7-8]
    - American Social Hygiene Association (Box 7)
      [7-9]
    - Ao-Az (Box 7)
      [7-10]
    - Applications for University Positions (Box 7)
      [7-11]
    - Baa-Bh (Box 7)
      [7-12]
    - Bates, Henry (Box 7)
      [7-13]
    - Beal, Junius (Box 7)
      [7-14]
    - Bi-Bn (Box 7)
      [7-15]
    - Bishop, William Warner (Box 7)
      [7-16]
    - Biology and Engineering Camps (Box 7)
      [7-17]
    - Bo-Brh (Box 7)
      [7-18]
    - Board in Control of Athletics (Box 7)
      [7-19]
    - Bri-Bt (Box 7)
      [7-20]
    - Buh-Bz (Box 7)
      [7-21]
    - Bumpus, H.C. (Box 7)
      [7-22]
    - Bursley, J.A. (Box 7)
      [7-23]
    - Caa-Cd (Box 7)
      [7-24]
    - Cabot, Hugh (Box 7)
      [7-25]
    - Cancer Research (Box 7)
      [7-26]
    - Carnegie Foundation Minutes (Box 7)
      [7-27]
    - Ce-Ch (Box 7)
      [7-28]
    - Ci-Cok (Box 8)
      [8-1]
    - Clements, William (Box 8)
      [8-2]
    - Col-Coz (Box 8)
      [8-3]
    - Committee on Appointments (Box 8)
      [8-4]
    - Committee-Deanship of Engineering (Box 8)
      [8-5]
    - Cooley, Mortimer Elwyn (Box 8)
      [8-6]
    - Cp-Cz (Box 8)
      [8-7]
    - Da-Dh (Box 8)
      [8-8]
    - Dana, Samuel Trask (Box 8)
      [8-9]
    - Day, E.C. (Box 8)
      [8-10]
    - Dean's Conference (Box 8)
      [8-11]
    - Dean of Engineering (Box 8)
      [8-12]
    - Deans-Potential (Box 8)
      [8-13]
    - Dedication Game October 22, 1927 (Box 8)
      [8-14]
    - Di-Doz (Box 8)
      [8-15]
    - Dormitories (Box 8)
      [8-16]
    - Dr-Dz (Box 8)
      [8-17]
    - Ea-Eh (Box 8)
      [8-18]
    - Effinger, John (Box 8)
      [8-19]
    - Ei-En (Box 8)
      [8-20]
    - Eo-Ez (Box 8)
      [8-21]
    - Executive Committee Matters (Box 8)
      [8-22]
    - Fa-Fq (Box 8)
      [8-23]
    - Faculty Research Fund (Box 8)
      [8-24]
    - Fr-Fz (Box 8)
      [8-25]
    - Ga-Gd (Box 8)
      [8-26]
    - Ge-Gh (Box 8)
      [8-27]
    - Gi-Gz (Box 8)
      [8-28]
    - Gifts (Box 8)
      [8-29]
    - Gore, Victor (Box 8)
      [8-30]
    - Green, Fred (Box 8)
      [8-31]
    - Haa-Has (Box 8)
      [8-32]
    - Hat-Haz (Box 9)
      [9-1]
    - Haynes, Harley A. (Box 9)
      [9-2]
    - Hea-Her (Box 9)
      [9-3]
    - Hes-Hn (Box 9)
      [9-4]
    - High School Inspection (Box 9)
      [9-5]
    - Hoa-Ht (Box 9)
      [9-6]
    - Housing Association (Box 9)
      [9-7]
    - Hua-Hz (Box 9)
      [9-8]
    - Hubbard, Lucius Lee (Box 9)
      [9-9]
    - Huber, Carl (Box 9)
      [9-10]
    - I (Box 9)
      [9-11]
    - Institute of International Education (Box 9)
      [9-12]
    - Ja-Jz (Box 9)
      [9-13]
    - Jack, P.M. (Box 9)
      [9-14]
    - K (Box 9)
      [9-15]
    - Laa-Lh (Box 9)
      [9-16]
    - Lawyers' Club Minutes (Box 9)
      [9-17]
    - League of Nations Non-Partisan Association (Box 9)
      [9-18]
    - Li-Lz (Box 9)
      [9-19]
    - Ma-Md (Box 9)
      [9-20]
    - Me-Mh (Box 9)
      [9-21]
    - Mi-Mn (Box 9)
      [9-22]
    - Michigan League-Alumni Council (Box 9)
      [9-23]
    - Moa-Mz (Box 9)
      [9-24]
    - Moore, Henry J. (Box 9)
      [9-25]